Guide to the Fernando Alegria Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 11. Photographs
  - Subseries B. Family and Friends
    - Family vacation to [Spain?], [196-], 64 photographs: b & w + negatives: b & w; Minox PX format (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Trip to [Apoguindo], Viña, Aeropuerto [Pudatisol?], n.d., 11 photographs: col. + negatives: col.; 35 mm. (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Trip: at Ramon Astorga's house & at Viña with Velascos, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Trip: at Santiago Alegria's house & at Luis Alegria's house, n.d., 36 negatives: col.; 35 m.. (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Trip to [Chile?], n.d., 16 photographs: col. + 24 negatives: col.; 35 m.. (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Fernando and Carmen Alegria at dinner party with friends, [198-] (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Friends, n.d., 9 photographs: col. + 1 photograph: b & w (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - House and grounds, Stanford, Calif. n.d. (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Victor Velasquez's house, Placa, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Barbeque at Alegria home, [197-], 16 slides: col.; 35 mm. (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous slides (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - Subseries C. Subject
    - Allende book: photographs (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Allende, Salvador. Funeral (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Amerika, Amerikka, Amerikkka photographs [1 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Amerika, Amerikka, Amerikkka photographs [2 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Amerikkka no. 2 fotos [1 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 5)
      Garry, Charles; Los Siete de la Raza
    - Amerikkka no. 2 fotos [2 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Artwork (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Photographic artwork / by Alejandro Stuart (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Caballos - Mexico = Horses - Mexico (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Caballos - USA: correspondence, recorts, photographs, etc. [1 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Caballos - USA: correspondence, recorts, photographs, etc. [2 of 2] (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Casa Pablo Neruda, Isla Negra, Chile (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Chile during military coup [1 of 2], 1973 Sept. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Chile during military coup [2 of 2], 1973 Sept. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Chile during military coup, no. 2, 1973 Sept. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Chile during military coup, no. 3, 1973 Sept. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Images of Chile, 1993 - 1997, photocopies of photographs (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - "Hounds" attacking Chileans [Courtesy of the Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley] (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Nicaraguan revolution: photographs / by Marcelo Montecino (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Park scenes (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Photographs / by Charles Fontsere (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified negatives, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - El Salvador: photographs, 5 photographs: b & w + tms (2 p.) (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Don Felipe: photograph, 1 photograph: b & w with hand-tinted color (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Demonstrator at the Escuela de Medicina Norte, University of Santiago, 1986 July, 1 photograph: b & w; mounted (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Photographic artwork / by Alejandro Stuart, 1971, 3 photographs: b & w; mounted (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Family tree, n.d., 2 photographs: col. (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Photographic montage / Diane Edwards La Voy 1972, 1 photograph: col. (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D. Conferences
    - Conferencia de Santiago, 1945 Jan. 6 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified conferences, [1940 - 1949] (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Conference of Latin American Writers, 1961 (Box 76, Folder 15)
      Alegria, Fernando Castellano, Rosario Fuentes, Carlos Vargas Llosa, Mario
    - Conference of Latin American Writers, 1961 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Escuela de Verano, 1962 Jan. 15 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - SHOW's First Inter-American Symposium, Paradise Island, Bahamas, 1962 Nov. 10-15 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Fernando Alegria at [cultural attache?] meeting, [196-] (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1960 - 1969 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Fernando Alegria at unidentified performance, [196-] (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified writer's conference [196-] (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified conference [196-] (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous conference 1960 - 1969 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Congreso del Instituto de Literatura Iberoamericana, 1971 Aug. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Illinois State University lecture, 1971 Nov. 8 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Fernando Alegria and others at unidentified workshop, ca. 1974 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Fernando Alegria at reading, ca. 1977 Apr. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Encuentro de Intelectuales por la Soberania de los Pueblos de Nuestra America, [197-] Sept. 4-7 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1970 - 1979 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Fernando Alegria at Congreso [?]lichex, Los Angeles, 1980 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Fernando Alegria at unidentified conference, ca. 1980 Jan., photographs + slides (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1980 - 1989 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Obermann seminar: Whitman and the world, 1992 [Apr.] (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Fernando Alegria and others at Congreso Internacional de Escritores, 1992 Aug. 26-30, 1 photograph: col.; 13 x 19 cm. (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - University of Southern California reading, ca. 1995 July (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1990 - 1999 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous readings, 1990 - 1999 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Fernando Alegria, Paul Schroeder, and [Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano] at reception, Stanford University, [199-] (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Fernando Alegria, Volodia, Luis Bocaz at unidentified conference, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Panel discussion re: Fernando Alegria's Allende, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified conference with Salvador Allende and Orlando Letelier in attendance, n.d., 10 negatives: b & w; 35 m.. (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified workshop, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Encuentro Latinoamericano de Escritores, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified conference in [Brazil], n.d., 4 slides: col.; 35 mm. (Box 77, Folder 25)
  - Subseries E. Authors & literary figures
    - Allende, Isabel (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Allende, Salvador (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Allende, Salvador (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Antunez, Nemesio (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Ernesto Barreda and photographs of his artwork (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - Bravo, Ernesto (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - Cortazar, [Julio?] (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Maria Eugenia (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Fuentes, Carlos (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Ginsberg, Allen (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - [Letelier], Orlando (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Miller, Yvette, editor and director, Latin American Review, Pittsburgh (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Neruda, Pablo (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Olano, Nora (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Onorio, Nelson (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Peron, Juan (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Picasso, Pablo (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Prado, Maria del (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified man (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified man (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified man, 1 negative: b & w (Box 78, Folder 10)
- Series 12. Computer files
  - Allende [computer file], 1988, 3 computer diskettes; 5.25 in. Word Perfect 3.X (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Allende [computer file], 1988, 7 computer diskettes; 5.25 in. Nota Bene 1.X (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Allende [computer file], n.d., 1 computer diskette; 3.5 in. Word Perfect 5.1 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Novela [computer file], n.d., 1 computer diskette; 5.25 in. (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Poesía Chilena [computer file], n.d., 2 computer diskettes; 3.5 in. (Box 78, Folder 14)
- Series 13. Audiovisual materials
  - Exilio - Mexico [videorecording], 1982, 1 videoreel (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - F.A. - Nina Serrano [videorecording], 1973 Oct., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Isabel y Angel [videorecording] / entrevista Carlos Baron, video Patricio Livingstone, 1985 Nov., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - A portrait of Nora [videorecording]: sample footage 1990, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Inauguración Exposicion "Pablo Neruda", Consulado de Chile en NY [videorecording], 1992 Apr. 28, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Fernando Alegria: Three ships of dreams: the self discovery of America [videorecording]. -- (Green Honors Lecture, Texas Christian University), 1992 Oct. 29, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (98 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Johnny Cien Pesos [videorecording]: with English subtitles, 1995 Oct. 10, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (92 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Ardiente paciencia [videorecording]: Pablo Neruda in Isla Negra / director, Antonio Skarmeta, n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Ballet Azul, Chile [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Carlos Lopez, Menlo Park [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Chavez-Taylor fight [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Claudio Arrau, Philadelphia Orchestra [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - El exilio de Gardel [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (120 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Los niños de Septiembre [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Supercamp [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (14 min.): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Sixty Minutes. Chile Segment: Los Quinados [videorecording], 1986 Nov. 23, 1 videocassette of 1 (Beta): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - A esta hora se improvisa [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (Beta): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Discurso del Comdte. Borge en la Asamblea de AMNLAE dedicada a la formación del Frente Regional de Madres y familiares de movilizados [videorecording], n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (Beta): sd., col.; 1/2 in. (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Borges, no. 1 [videorecording] / J. Barrios, n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Borges, no. 2 [videorecording] / J. Barrios, n.d., 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Horizons. H-6-82. Chile [videorecording], 1982, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Nicaragua, No. 1. And also teach them to read [videorecording], 1982, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (60 min.): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Nicaragua, No. 2. Five months that changed a nation [videorecording], 1982 July 23, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (60 min.): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Reunion de escritores [videorecording]. -- (Programa Especial Bellas Artes, no. 1345-A), 1982 Nov. 26, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS) (47 min.): sd., col.; 3/4 in. (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Fernando Alegria. SECH - Julio S. lectura [sound recording], 1984, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Fernando Alegria. Santiago del Nuevo Extremo [sound recording], 1971 Apr. 29, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - KPFA. David Guss - Fernando Alegria. A conversation about Vicente Huidobro [sound recording], 1976 Aug. 28, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Longshoreman Hall, Fernando Alegria, etc.; At La Peña. Fernando Alegria: poems to Allende [sound recording], 1975 Sept. 11, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Diálogo con Fernando Alegría, Mexico / D.L. Pilly [sound recording], 1976 Aug. 11, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Fernando Alegria: report / by Christian Opaso [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Una noche de Alegria, Peña del Sur [sound recording], 1994 Sept. 24, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Fernando Alegria [sound recording]: Discurso y poema; Entrevista de F. Alegria y Angel e Isabel Parra; Introduccion a chilenos en Calif., n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Señora Allende [sound recording]: Spanish version; Señora Allende: English version, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Salvador Allende. Palabras de lucha y esperanza [sound recording]. -- Santiago, Chile: MAPU, 1979, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Aparcoa at Longshoreman's Hall [sound recording], 1976 Sept. 11, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Gallito de la pasion: Fernando Alegria, Aparcoa [in] New York [sound recording], 1976 Sept. 11, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Joan Baez, Frost Amphitheatre [sound recording], 1973 Sept. 30, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - [Joan] Baez [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Joakin Bello [sound recording]: Demo - films, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Jorge Ben [sound recording]; Ast[r]ud Gilberto; S. Mendez; Baden Powell / M. Einhorn, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Entrevista [sound recording]: Antonio Benitez Rojo, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Bola de nieve [sound recording]: in memoriam, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - J.L. Borges [sound recording], 1972 Mar. 18, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Borges [sound recording]: entrevista por una vieja idiota ...., n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 20)
  - Soledad Bravo [sound recording]: Venezuela at La Peña, 1976 Mar. 5, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 21)
  - Cortázar and Alegría [sound recording]: prose reading / trans. read by Stephen Kessler, 1980 Oct. 27, 1 sound cassette (cy 1) (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Cortázar and Alegría [sound recording]: prose reading / trans. read by Stephen Kessler, 1980 Oct. 27, 1 sound cassette (cy 2) (Box 82, Folder 23)
  - Verónica de Negro [sound recording]: Rod. Rojas, 1987 June 20, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 24)
  - Dialogando con el criollismo [sound recording]. -- (No. 92-1) [1992?], 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 25)
  - Discurso T. Borges [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - Espejo de Escritores. Isabel Allende. -- Hanover, NH: Ediciones del Norte [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 27)
  - Feature Borges [sound recording] / Brent Goff, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 28)
  - Festival de la Nueva Canción, Quito, Ecuador [sound recording], 1984 July 8-15, 1 sound cassette: Dolby (Box 82, Folder 29)
  - Gardel [sound recording]: Tangos viejos, n.d.`, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 30)
  - Mario Gomez Lopez [sound recording]: Recuerdos del Bosco, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 31)
  - Homenaje a Fernando Alegria [sound recording] 1980 May 20, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 32)
  - Il Bosco [sound recording]: Manuel Alvarez (Garzon), n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 33)
  - Il Bosco [sound recording]: Entrevista Sr. Jose Oxarzon, Jefe de personal n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 34)
  - Il Bosco [sound recording]: Ernesto Urra (actor) n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 35)
  - Inti-Illimani [sound recording]: La Peña, 1976 Mar. 7, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 36)
  - Canto a Gabriela [sound recording] / Rafael Manriguez, 1990, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 37)
    Ronda de la Celba Ecuatoriana -- Constelaciones -- La cuento mundo -- El aire y la luz -- El agua -- Pinar y fuego -- La tierra
  - Manuelitos y [Menorca?] una noche en Sept. 1982 [sound recording] -- Noticias SP 1982 Sept. 13, 1 sound cassette (Box 82, Folder 38)
  - Musica y dialogo. Program 146. Interview with Fernando Alegria, Part 1 [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Musica y dialogo. Program 146. Interview with Fernando Alegria, Part 2 [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - New song [sound recording]: voices and visions of the Americas. Part I: The origins / B. Goff, A. Merrim, n.d., 1 sound cassette (59 min.) (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - New song [sound recording]: voices and visions of the Americas. Part II: The images / B. Goff, A. Merrim, n.d., 1 sound cassette (59 min.) (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - New song [sound recording]: voices and visions of the Americas. Part III / B. Goff, A. Merrim n.d., 1 sound cassette (59 min.) (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Opera do Malandro [sound recording]: Chico Buarque de Hollanda, 1980 Feb. 18, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Angel - Isabel Parra [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Isabel Parra [sound recording]: De chile & Vientos del pueblo n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Violeta Parra [sound recording]: Santiago, Penando estas. -- (Cile canta e lotta, no. 2). -- Italy: Albatros, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Violeta Madre [sound recording]: four part series on the life and work of Violetta Parra. Parts 1 & 2 / produced and narrated by Lisa Levy n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Violeta Madre [sound recording]: four part series on the life and work of Violetta Parra. Parts 3 & 4 / produced and narrated by Lisa Levy n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Chile 1978 [sound recording]: ¡¡Paz, justicia, libertad!! 1978, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - The poet's voice [sound recording]: Pablo Neruda. -- New York: n.d., 1 sound cassette (29 min.) (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Quilapayún [sound recording]: concierto grabado, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Quilapayún [sound recording]: patria, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Quilapayún [sound recording]: alentours, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Quilapayún [sound recording]: anarchas, patria, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Dr. J. Quiroga [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Antologia del cuple [sound recording]: lo visto y no visto de Olga Ramos / Olga Ramos n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Unicornio [sound recording] / Silvio Rodriguez, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Romancero español [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Juan Rulfo, Santa Clara University [sound recording], 1982 Nov. 2, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 22)
  - Juan Rulfo, Stanford University [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - NPR Playhouse. No. 840821, Faces, mirrors, masks [sound recording] / Juan Rulfo. -- [S.l.]: National Public Radio, 1984, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - Semblanza radiofónica de Gabriela Mistral [sound recording]: fonocarta de JC a RB, Nov. 1976 & Programa Deutsche Welle / R. Bada, 1984 Feb. 13, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 25)
  - Mercedes Sosa en Argentina [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 26)
  - Mercedes Sosa en Argentina [sound recording]. Unicornio / Silvio Rodriguez, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 27)
  - Amo el Canto del Censuntle [sound recording]; Grito de la tierra / Mercedes Sosa, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 28)
  - Los sucesos chilenos [sound recording]; Musica de acordeón, 1968; 1973, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 29)
  - A surprise for Fernando [sound recording]: 4 songs, incomplete, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 30)
  - Victor Valenzuela on Chile [sound recording]: Parts I & II, 1986, 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 31)
  - Coplas [sound recording] / Atahualpa Yupanqui, n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 32)
  - Untitled [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound cassette (Box 83, Folder 33)
  - Act's [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 84)
  - Unidentified [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 85)
  - Fernando Alegria [sound recording]: poems and songs and interview, KPFA / Matthew Zion, 1968 June, 1 sound tape reel; analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Fernando Alegria II [sound recording], 1971 Apr. 29, 1 sound tape reel (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Salvador Allende [sound recording]: last speech, Santiago, Chile, 1973 Sept. 11, 1 sound tape reel (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Jorge Luis Borges [sound recording]: the contemporary literary scence in Buenos Aires. Brother Antoninus: poetry reading from his own works, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3-3/4 ips, monophone, 2 tracks (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Bresil y sertao favelas [sound recording] / Zelia Barbosa, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Brotando del silencio [sound recording] / Suni Paz, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Encuentros de Escritores en la Universidad de Concepción [sound recording]: con Ferlinghetti - F. Alegria, estación KPFA, Berkeley. Poesia de Pablo Neruda: odas y patrioticas, 1960 May 7, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 ips (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Entrevista en KGEI, 1956 Jan. [sound recording]; Entrevista, KPFA, 1955 Sept.; 1956 Jan., 1 sound tape reel (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - An evening with Carl Sandburg [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3-3/4 ips, 2 tracks, monophone (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Federico Garcia Lorca [sound recording]: sinfonia poetica, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Festival del Sexto Sol [sound recording]: 40 minute report with music, narration, and poetry / prod. by Comunicacio Aztlen, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Grabación clandestina de la despedida de Angel Parra del campo de concentracion Chacabuco [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Changuita Guerillero, et al. [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Nicolas Guillen dice sus poemas [sound recording]. Carola Yonmar / Federico Garcia Lorca, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips, monophonic, 2 tracks (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - An interview with Brother Antoninus, 1958 Aug. 13 [sound recording]. Spanish American poetry, 1957 May 1, 1 sound tape reel (60 min.): analog, 3-3/4 ips (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Inti-Illimani [sound recording]: concierto en Stanford University, 1974. Quilapayún: concierto en Berkeley Community Theater, 1975, 1 sound tape reel (cy 1) (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Inti-Illimani [sound recording]: concierto en Stanford University, 1974. Quilapayún: concierto en Berkeley Community Theater, 1975, 1 sound tape reel (cy 2) (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Musica de Cuba [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - 20 poemas de amor y una canción desesperada [sound recording]: enterpretación de su autor / Pablo Neruda, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - La nueva canción chilena [sound recording] / Violeta Parra & Victor Parra, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Oppenheimer interview [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Violeta Parra [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Octavio Paz [sound recording]: poesia: voz del autor, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Ines Pinto [sound recording], 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Poems [sound recording] / by Federico Garcia Lorca, et al., n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips + 3-3/4 ips (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Carlos Puebla, Cuba [sound recording]. Noel Hernandez, Puerto Rico, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3-3/4 ips (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Sibellius [sound recording]: Nicolas Guillen dice sus poemas, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 3)